Contact

+977 9843623018 (Mobile) mail@surendrashrestha.info. np

www.linkedin.com/in/surendra37 (LinkedIn) surendrashrestha.info.np (Portfolio)

Top Skills

Amazon Web Services (AWS)
Code Development
Code Deployment

Certifications

Learning SOLID Programming Principles

Upwork Skill Certification - C# Development

Foundational C# with Microsoft Certification

AWS Certified Developer – Associate

Surendra Shrestha

Senior Software Engineer

Kathmandu, Bāgmatī, Nepal

Summary

** result-oriented **| **6+ years of experience** | **C#** | **.NET Framework** | **.NET Core** | **WPF** | **Windows Forms** | ** ETL ** | ** SQL Databases** | ** Web Scraping ** | ** Installer **

I am a result-oriented developer with a medium to expert level of experience in Windows desktop software development. For the last two years, my preferred technologies are C#/.NET/.NET CORE, WPF, MVVM, Entity Framework, and MS SQL Server. I always use the latest technologies and best practices, so you can be sure that you will get the highest possible quality. Client satisfaction is the most important for me.

Over the year of working, I have gained expertise that covers:

- ✓ Architecting your next enterprise-level software solution
- ✓ Programming anything from your imagination to a solution.
- ✓ Restful API Development
- ✓ Web Application Development
- ✓ Desktop Application Development
- ✓ SQL Database
- ✓ Debugging and maintenance of existing desktop applications
- ✓ Web scraping
- ✓ ETL ✓ Batch/Bulk/Distributed processing
- ✓ Certified Amazon Web Service (AWS) Developer

My technical skillset includes:

- √ C# ✓ .NET Framework ✓ .NET CORE
- ✓ ASP.NET (Web-Forms, MVC, Core)
- ✓ WPF ✓ Windows Forms ✓ MVVM ✓ Material Design UI
- ✓ Microsoft SQL Server ✓ PostgreSQL ✓ MySQL ✓ SQLite
- ✓ Selenium ✓ Playwright ✓ RestSharp ✓ HtmlAgilityPack
- ✓ Docker ✓AWS
- ✓ RabbitMQ

I am a hardworking, focused, and effective team player. I have high motivation, extensive knowledge, good logical and problem-solving skills.

I am here to help you and bring your projects to life! Regards, Surendra

Experience

Verisk

Senior Software Engineer April 2023 - Present (1 year 5 months)

Kathmandu, Bāgmatī, Nepal

- # Extract, Transform, Load (ETL) using Pentaho
- # Batch data processing on huge volume of data (.NET 5)
- # BDD Testing using Spec flow
- # Dependency Injection Autofac, Microsoft DI
- # AWS Certified Developer Associate

Upwork

Freelance Software Engineer January 2021 - April 2023 (2 years 4 months) Kathmandu, Bāgmatī, Nepal

- # Web scraping and plugin development for wordpress for TradingView charts, login and more...
- # Selenium WebDriver and RestSharp for Web Scraping
- # Windows application for social media app for gamers
- # Multipurpose automation tools for different behavior
- # .NET Core Web API for accessing MS SQL database
- # .NET Core client consuming the API (Winform+WPF app)
- # Database synchronization using .NET (ETL)
- # Task scheduler based jobs to run on schedule
- # Generate installer file (MSI)
- # Social media application for gamers

Asteroid Venture (AV)
Software Engineer
December 2018 - January 2022 (3 years 2 months)
Nepal

- # Started working on Enterprise Content Management (ECM) Migration Software.
- # Worked on migration of data from different ECM system to Microsoft's Sharepoint.
- # Worked on ECM system analyzer tool
- # Worked on Window's Communication Foundation (WCF) system and SQLite/ SQLCe databases.
- # Worked as a Window's Presentation Framework (WPF) developer for analyzer tools.
- # Consuming SOAP and REST API
- #.NET Core

DOTMARK SOLUTIONS LTD

.NET Developer

December 2017 - December 2018 (1 year 1 month)

Nepal

- # Started Programming career as a .NET Software programmer.
- # Got involved on Desktop application for health/hospital management system.
- # Worked on Windows Presentation Framework (WPF).
- # Used Microsoft's 'Prism Framework' for MVVM (Model View ViewModel) implementation.
- # Worked in NodeJS using Express Framework for API development.

Institute of Engineering Thapathali Campus Student

January 2014 - December 2017 (4 years)

Nepal

- # Joined Bachelor in Engineering in Electronics and Communication Engineering
- # Developed 'Beam Analysis' Software as Minor project, to calculate shear force and bending moments at different point using Microsoft's Window's Form Application.
- # Participated in different boot camp programs organized by NCELL, Microsoft, etc.
- # Created 'Speaker Recognition System' as Major Project, using Python as a programming language using Mel-Frequency Cepstrum Co-efficient (MFCC) to recognize the User based on their audio input.

Robotics and Automation Center, Thapathali Campus Hardware Programmer 2014 - 2017 (3 years)

Nepal

Joined Robotics and Automation Center

Worked on a team to create simple task completing robots and program it to perform those tasks using C programming language.

Participated in International Robotics Competition (IRC) held in Mumbai, India for two times.

Education

Institute of Engineering Thapathali Campus
Bachelor of Engineering - BE, Electronics and Communications
Engineering · (2014 - 2018)

Reliance International Academy
Intermediate Science, Computer Science · (2011 - 2013)